International Ladies Garment Workers Union. Schlesinger, Benjamin, President. Records, 1914-1923. 5780/009
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series II. Subject Files.
  - C. Locals.
    - Local 25 (Ladies Waist and Dressmakers' Union) Union, Includes letter to Louis D. Brandeis (chairman), Board of Arbitration, from Chief Clerks of Local and Dress and Waist Manufacturers Association on problem in Dress and Waist Makers Industry, 1914. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Local 25: 1916-21., Includes letters from Solomon Polakoff, Isidore Schoenholtz; reports. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Local 28 (Ladies Garment Workers, Seattle, Wash.) 1914-21. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Local 30 (Cutters and Trimmers of Cincinnati) 1919 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Local 32, 1918. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Local 33 (Corset Workers' Union) 1915-20. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Local 34 (Corset Cutters' Union) 1922. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Local 35 (Cloak, Skirt and Dress Pressers' Union), 1914-22., Includes correspondence with A.E. Kazan (Secretary-Treasurer), 1914-15; Joseph Breslaver (Breslaw), Manager, 1917-1918. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Local 37 (Pressers Union) 1915. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Local 38 (Ladies Tailors and Dressmakers' Union) 1912-1916., Including charge by Merchants' Society of Ladies Tailors and Dressmakers' and counter-charges against them by Local, 1912; correspondence between Merchants Society of Ladies Tailors and Local on negotiations for agreement, 1914-1916; undated letters. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Local 39-40 (Corset Workers Union), New Haven, Conn. 1919 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Local 41 (Wrapper, Kimono and House Dress Makers' Union), 1914-1916. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Local 43 (Ladies Waist and White Goods Workers Union), Worcester, Mass, 1918-1919. Including letters from Local officers, Samuel Cohen and Sigmund Haiman. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Local 44 (Chicago Cloakmakers' Union), 1914-1915., Letters from Hyman Schoolman and F. Finkler. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Local 44, 1916-1917 (Changed to Local 5, ca. 1919.), Correspondence with Hyman Schoolman on organizing, negotiating agreements. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Local 45, 1918., Letters from National Alliance of Ladies Cloaks and Suits Designers on application for charter. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Local 48 (Italian Cloak, Suit and Skirtmakers' Union), 1916. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Local 49 (Waist, Dress and Petticoat Workers' Union), Boston, 1916-1917., Includes letters from Samuel Jacobson. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Local 49: 1918-1922., Continued correspondence with Samuel Jacobson. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Local 50 (Misses and Children's Dressmakers' Union), 1916-18., Letters from Harry Greenberg. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Local 52, Los Angeles 1914, 1918-1919., Includes correspondence with Morris Biell (Business Agent); M. Michaelson (President), Cloak and Suit Manufacturers; Charles T. Connell, U.S. Commission of Conciliation, Dept. of Labor, on 1919 strike in L.A. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Local 52, 1920-1922. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - D. Subject Files, M-Z.
    - Marshall, Louis, 1915-1922., Includes letter requesting Schlesinger to write President to veto immigration bill, 1915; Abraham Cahan letter to Louis Marshall stating policy of paper (Jewish Daily Forward) with regard to criticizing government during war, Oct. 1917; correspondence on conditions between Union and Cloak and Suit firm, R. Sadowsky, 1921-22. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Mayor's Council of Conciliation in the Cloak and Suit Industry (New York, N.Y.), July 1915-April 1916., Correspondence with Felix Adler (Chairman), mayor's council; Henry Bruère (Vice Chairman); letter from Mayor John P. Mitchel; copies of letters between John B. Stanchfield, Employers Council and Jacob Panken, Council for union, on negotiations to avert strike in industry. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Mayor's Office (New York, N.Y.) 1916-1919., Letters requesting Schlesinger to serve on committees, 1916-17; correspondence with Mayor John Hylan on controversy between Union and Dress and Waist Manufacturers Association, 1919. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Sigman, Morris., Two letters, Oct. 1922, Jan. 1923. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - United Garment Workers of America, 1914-1920., Includes letters to U.G.W. requesting alliance of garment workers' unions, June 1920. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - United Ladies Trade Union, London, England, 1920-1922. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - United Mine Workers of America, 1922., Includes letters from William Green (Secretary-Treasurer) on Union contribution to striking coal miners. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - United Textile Workers of America, 1916-1922., Includes correspondence with John Golden (President) on jurisdictional dispute over embroidery workers, 1916. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Untermyer, Samuel, 1919-22., Includes correspondence on candidacy of Irwin Untermyer for Supreme Court Justice in New York, 1919. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Waterproof Garment Manufacturers' Association, 1915-1918., Correspondence on arrangements to avert strike in industry. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Wholesale Dress Manufacturers' Association, 1919-1922., Correspondence with Alfred Lyons (Manager), Jacob Siegal (President) on negotiations for agreements. (Box 4, Folder 22)